Louisa Chase Papers
Louisa Chase Papers
1971-2016
Chase, Louisa, 1951-2016.
25 linear ft.
Artwork: original and reproductions, corespondence subject files, writings and memorabilia of the American painter.
4994197
Biographical History
Louisa Chase (1951-2016) was an American painter. Born in Panama where her father was stationed in the Army, she grew up in Pennsylvania. She obtaned her BA degree in printmaking from Syracuse University in 1973 and a Master's degree from Yale in 1975. Based in Manhattan, she exhibited widely and taught at Rhode Island School of design, The School of Visual Arts and at The Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture. She is best know for known for her paintings in the New Image style.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Louisa Chase Papers comprises Biographical material, Artwork, original; Artwork, reproductions; Correspondence-subject files, Financial and legal files, Medical files, Writings and Memorabilia.
Biographical material consists of her curriculum vitae and biographical sketches composed for exhibitions.
Artwork original includes sketch books and some loose drawings.
Artwork reproductions consists of high quality transparancies, prints and negatives comprising an extensive record of the artist's work.
Correspondence-subject files consists of Ms. Chase's correspondence with family, friends, galleries and institutions.
Financial and legal files is a single folder of income, tax, real estate, insurance and sales receipts.
Medical files is a single folder of research notes on cancer and correspondence with doctors.
Writings include a personal journal as well as poems and essays.
Memorabilia consists of exhibition catalogs, personal and family photographs, a collection of music CDs compiled by Ms. Chase and assorted miscellaneous material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Artwork is arranged as the artist filed it. Some is chronological and some is grouped in other ways that may be less obvious. Correspondence subject files are arranged alphabetically and everything else is arranged by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Chase, Louisa, 1951-2016.; Barosh, Miyoshi.; Chihuly, Dale, 1941-; Gold, Alison Leslie.; Guston, Philip, 1913-1980.; Lauterbach, Ann, 1942-; Leveque, Pierre, 1921-2004.;; Painters -- United States -- 20th century.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Women artists -- United States.; Women painters -- United States.; Exhibition catalogs.; Sketches.; Essays.; Photographs.; Photographic transparencies.; Black-and-white negatives.; Color negatives.; Videocassettes.; Diaries.; CD-ROMs.; Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Louisa Chase Estate, 2017.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
- Artwork, original
  - Sketchbooks, undated; 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Sketchbooks, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Artwork, reproductions
  - Mixed types, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Negatives, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Prints, undated; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Prints, 1979-1984; 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Prints, 1985-1989; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Prints, 1990-1997, undated; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Prints, undated (Oversize 5)
  - Transparencies, 1979-1980; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Transparencies, 1980-1981; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Transparencies, 1982; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Transparencies, 1982-1983; 6 folders (Box 8)
  - Transparencies, 1983-1987; 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Transparencies, 1987-1988; 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Transparencies, 1989-1990; 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Transparencies, 1990-1992, undated; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Transparencies, 1970-1973; 10 folders (Box 12)
  - Transparencies, 1972-2003, undated; 30 folders (Box 13)
  - Transparencies, undated; 11 folders (Box 14)
  - Transparencies, 1979-1994; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Transparencies, undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Transparencies, undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Transparencies, 1978-1988 (Box 18)
  - Transparencies, 1984-1997 (Box 18)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Astier, Pierre, 1987 (Box 19)
  - Bank America Corporation Art Program, 1982-1985 (Box 19)
  - Barosh, Miyoshi, 1986, undated (Box 19)
  - Berard, Guy, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Betsy Rosenfeld Gallery, Inc., 1987 (Box 19)
  - The Broad Art Foundation, 2001 (Box 19)
  - Brooke Alexander Gallery New York, 1982-1996 (Box 19)
  - The Brooklyn Museum, 1989 (Box 19)
  - The Butler Institute of American Art, 1998 (Box 19)
  - California State University, Long Beach, 1998 (Box 19)
  - Caraccio, Kathy, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Chase, Ben, undated (Box 19)
  - Chase, Wilda S., undated (Box 19)
  - Chihuly, Dale, undated (Box 19)
  - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, 1987 (Box 19)
  - Foundation for the Community if Artists, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Gold, Alison Leslie, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Goya-Girl Press, Inc., 1972; 2000-2001 (Box 19)
  - Guston, Philip, 1975 (Box 19)
  - The Hayground School Bridgehampton, New York, 2003 (Box 19)
  - Hirshorn Museum, 1984 (Box 19)
  - Holzman, Eric, 2011 (Box 19)
  - Inflatable sculpture, 1972 (Box 19)
  - International Print Center New York (IPCNY), 2001 (Box 19)
  - Lauterbach, Ann, 1981-1984, undated (Box 19)
  - Lauterbach, Ann, undated (Oversize 5)
  - Leveque, Pierre, undated (Box 19)
  - Loyola University of Los Angeles, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1984; 1988 (Box 19)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1983 (Box 19)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Oliver, Bobbie, 1998 (Box 19)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1984 (Box 19)
  - Scott, Dale, 1982-1986 (Box 19)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Stengel, Avis E., 1989 (Box 19)
  - Tandem Press, 1987 (Box 19)
  - University of Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Vrej, Baghoomian, Inc., 1989 (Box 19)
  - Walker Art Center Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1984 (Box 19)
  - Yale University, 2001 (Box 19)
  - Zwerenz, Uli, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1979-1997, undated; 5 folders (Box 20)
- Financial and legal files
  - Financial and legal files (Box 20)
- Medical files
  - Medical files (Box 20)
- Writings
  - Essays and poems, undated (Box 21)
  - Journals, 1987-1988 (Box 21)
  - Journals, 2001 (Oversize 5)
  - Journals, 2016 (Box 21)
  - Notebooks, 2 folders (Box 21)
- Memorabilia
  - Addresses, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Architectural plans (Box 21)
  - Clippings (Box 21)
  - Diploma, 1975 (Oversize 5)
  - Exhibition and gallery announcements, 1977-2011; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1971-1980; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1979-1984 (Oversize 2)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1981-1984; 7 folders (Box 23)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1984-1986; 7 folders (Box 24)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1986-1991 (Oversize 3)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1987-1991; 8 folders (Box 25)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1992 (Oversize 4)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1993-2003; 6 folders (Box 26)
  - Mix CDs (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs
    - Family photographs (Box 26)
    - Portraits, 1981 (Box 26)
    - Portraits, 1983 (Box 26)
    - Portraits, 2001 (Box 26)
    - Portraits, undated; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Portraits, undated (Oversize 5)
    - Portraits, undated (Oversize 6)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 5 folders (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 11 folders (Box 28)
  - Records of shows and lists of paintings, 1971-1985, undated (Box 28)
  - Research material, undated (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified videocassette (Box 31)